Todor Tochev

10 bis avenue des Gobelins 75005 Paris France

tstochev@gmail.com ttochev.github.io +336 75 33 07 03

Economist working on the evaluation of public policies with a focus on labour markets and public assistance programmes. Speciality in applied causal inference and econometrics with big datasets. Experienced in using R, Stata, Python, Julia, SQL to analyse administrative datasets, internal company databases, and surveys. Presented insights to academics and policy makers.

RESEARCH SKILLS

Microeconometrics: Randomized Control Trials, Difference-in-Differences, Regression Discontinuity Design, Bunching.

Big Data: Analysed employment, vocational training and fiscal databases covering country-size populations (400+ million observations).

Project management: As Principal Investigator, directed a team of 10+ research assistants coordinating data collection, transcription, cleaning and analysis.

Data collection: Survey questionnaire design and programming for hand-held devices and websites, web analytics, acquisition and cleaning of company operational databases.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Economics, University of Warwick, 2023. Dissertation title: Essays in Applied Microeconomics

MRes. Economics, University of Warwick, 2018 (Distinction)
MSc. Economics, University of Warwick, 2014 (Distinction)

BSc. Business Administration, University of Bath, 2011 (Upper Second)

RESEARCH

Credit Constraints and Training Subsidies for Job-Seekers: Evidence from France

Take-up of Social Programs: Experimental Evidence from France, joint with Laura Castell, Marc Gurgand and Clément Imbert, R&R at American Economic Journal: Economic Policy

Do Localised Lockdowns Cause Labour Market Spillovers?, joint with Gabriele Guaitoli

Returns to Adult Vocational Education for Job-Seekers: Evidence from a Regression Discontinuity Design (work in progress)

Distance Learning and Sectoral Employment Programmes, joint with Audrey Rain (work in progress)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2023– Postdoctoral Fellow, Paris School of Economics (Paris, France)

2018– Affiliated Researcher, Research Directorate, Ministry of Labour (Paris, France)

2014–16 **Research Associate, JPAL Europe** (Paris, France)

Work on randomized evaluations: coordination with stakeholders, data collection and analysis. Projects in education, public, development economics.

2014 Research Assistant, University of Warwick

Cleaning large fiscal datasets and estimation of taxable income elasticities.

2011-12 Business Analyst, Astra Asset Management (Sofia, Bulgaria)

Portfolio analysis and regulatory compliance.

GRANTS AND AWARDS

2022 Covid Academic Support Fund PhD Grant (Royal Economic Society)

2021 Fondation du Risque, Chaire Sécurisation des Parcours Professionels Grant Award (€100,000, PI)

2018–22 ESRC Collaborative Studentship (University of Warwick & Ministry of Labour of France)

2011 L'Oréal Prize for Best Performing Student in Business and the Natural Environment (University of Bath)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: R, Stata, Python, Julia, SAS, SQL Questionnaire administration: ODK, SurveyCTO

OS: Windows, Linux